hello grammarians today we're going to
be talking about the irregular plural
previously I had said that if you take
any English word any noun say the word
dog and you tackiness onto the end of it
like so you get the word dogs and that's
how you form the plural in all cases I
was lying sorry it turns out that
English is a little bit more complicated
than that
while adding an S two things is the way
you usually make things plural sometimes
there are other changes and sometimes
you don't even paralyzed using an S at
the end but we're not gonna talk about
that now that's for another time but i
wanna talk about today is the most basic
kind of irregular plural so we have the
difference in English between regular
and irregular plurals and remember a
plural is when there's more than one of
something that comes from the Latin plus
which means as opposed to the singular
when there is just one of something
you know 11 dog two dogs so there's a
handful of words in English and it
really is a handful that don't plural
eyes regularly words like leaf loaf calf
cowboy if you try to play realized these
as though they were irregular plurals
you're going to return something that is
not correct or at least is not
conventional within modern standard
American English right so Leafs for
example unless you're talking about the
Toronto hockey team is not correct in
fact the proper term
boop boop boop is in fact leaves it is
not low but tasty loaves of bread it is
not calf's but cash so there are several
different kinds of irregular plurals
that's why this video is called the part
1 but I'm only going to cover one such
irregular plural today and that is the
change from Cingular F to plural ve so
if you see a word generally that ends in
F the plural is going to become ve you
can learn anything
David out